Yes, yes,
ừ ừ
and listen,
và
monks, there are three parts belonging to
này Các tỷ-kheo có ba phần thuộc về
the giver and three parts belonging to
người bố thí và có ba phần thuộc về
the recipient of the food alms. What are the
người nhận thực phẩm bố thí Thế nào là
three parts belonging to the giver?
ba phần thuộc về người bố thí này các
The giver, before giving,
tỷ-kheo người bố thí trước khi bố thí ý
is pleased; while giving, is
được vui lòng trong khi bố thí âm được
pure in mind; after giving, feels joyful.
Tịnh tín sau khi bố thí cảm thấy hoan hỉ
This is the giver's part. What
đây là bao phần của người bố thí Thế nào
are the three parts belonging to the recipient of the alms?
là ba phần của người nhận tẩm vật bố thí
Here, monks, the recipients of the
ở đây này các tỷ-kheo những người nhận
alms have attained detachment or are
phẩm vật Bố thí đã được Ly tham hay đang
practicing the detachment; have attained nissin or are practicing the nissin
thực hành Hạnh Ly tham đã được Nissin
or are practicing the giving. This
nici Hay đang thực hành Hạnh lì xì đây
is the recipient's part. And listen, monks,
là bao phần của người nhận phẩm vật bố
this
thí Như và này Các tỷ-kheo đây là thí
alms has six parts.
vật có 6 phần
The merit of the six parts of alms is
này Các tỷ-kheo công đức của Thúy vật 6
immeasurable. The source of merit
phần thật vô lượng là nguồn xanh Phước
is the source of blessings. Goodness, the food, the pleasure, belongs to the
là nguồn xanh Thiện món ăn ăn lạc thuộc
heavenly realm, the fruit of bliss. The food reaches the
thiên giới là quả lạc dị Thục rất đến
heavenly realm, leading to the possibility of
cõi trời đưa đến khả năng khả gì hạnh
happiness and peace. (This is a sutra on almsgiving and
phúc và an lạc chích bài kinh bố thí và
offerings, as in the Vietnamese Buddhist Canon, the
cúng dường như pháp đại tạng kinh Việt
three parts.)  The Devas
Nam tăng chi bộ ba phẩm Chư Thiên phần
bestow their blessings.
bố thí à